<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nikitas-theo.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://nikitas-theo.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-25T12:53:58+00:00</updated><id>https://nikitas-theo.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website for Nikitas Theodoropoulos. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Recommendations</title><link href="https://nikitas-theo.github.io/blog/2025/textbooks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recommendations"/><published>2025-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nikitas-theo.github.io/blog/2025/textbooks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nikitas-theo.github.io/blog/2025/textbooks/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3> <p>I’ve always been interested in learning new things and diving deeply into a topic. For this reason, I make a habit of collecting and evaluating learning resources, for all the various subjects I am interested in. In an effort to assist others who, like me, might be looking for the best way to approach a new area of interest, I have curated here a list of resources I’ve collected over the years. Disclaimer: on many (all) of these I am not an expert, and I am just sharing my personal views and experience:)</p> <h4 id="general-machine-learning">General Machine Learning</h4> <p>Deep Learning book by Ian Goodfelow and Yashua Bengio, continues to be an excellent textbook, even in the modern ML landscape — 10 years later. Notation and writing can be a little dense, but nevertheless, It was a valuable resource for me.</p> <h4 id="natural-language-processing">Natural Language Processing</h4> <p>The classic reccomended read for modern NLP is Speech and Language Processing Dan Jurafsky and James H. Martin, available for free as a draft <a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~jurafsky/slp3/">here</a>.</p> <p>I personally really reccomend the video series of Karpathy. Both, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VMj-3S1tku0&amp;list=PLAqhIrjkxbuWI23v9cThsA9GvCAUhRvKZ">Neural Networks: Zero to Hero</a> and his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zjkBMFhNj_g&amp;list=PLAqhIrjkxbuW9U8-vZ_s_cjKPT_FqRStI">General Audience videos</a> about AI. One instructive repo on training LMs is <a href="https://github.com/karpathy/nanoGPT">nanoGPT</a></p> <h4 id="linguistics-for-nlp">Linguistics (for NLP)</h4> <h4 id="statistics">Statistics</h4> <h4 id="cognitive-sciecne">Cognitive Sciecne</h4> <h4 id="music-theory">Music Theory</h4> <h4 id="science-fiction">Science Fiction</h4> <h4 id="classic-literature">Classic Literature</h4>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction I’ve always been interested in learning new things and diving deeply into a topic. For this reason, I make a habit of collecting and evaluating learning resources, for all the various subjects I am interested in. In an effort to assist others who, like me, might be looking for the best way to approach a new area of interest, I have curated here a list of resources I’ve collected over the years. Disclaimer: on many (all) of these I am not an expert, and I am just sharing my personal views and experience:)]]></summary></entry></feed>